thank you
amen amen amen a happy Sabbath everyone
um
put a one in the chat if you all are
ready to get into the word
today
I want to welcome you uh also welcoming
our Instagram uh friends family
um we are going to be talking about a
very important subject today I think
it's a question that
uh everyone asks at some point in their
life and the question is what is truth
what is truth
the title of my message today
is called simply the most powerful
testimony the most powerful testimony so
here's who needs to be watching this
today if if you are a person who is
searching for truth
if you are a person who
who doubts
that one can actually find truth
if you're a person that is confused
about how to find truth because you see
all these different religions
all claiming to have truth
uh this message is for you today I'm
gonna actually go a step further and ask
you if you know someone like that go
ahead and share this link with that
person not invite that person or those
people now
to come and watch this message
so we're going to pray and we're going
to jump in because we're going to be
covering some very
powerful powerful things here
today so I'm going to invite you to just
uh where you are about your heads with
me let's pray Heavenly Father
bless us Lord as we answer this question
as we seek to answer the question what
is truth
we pray this I pray you would speak
through me Lord in Jesus name I ask it
amen amen so
let's go to the slides and for those of
you that are watching on Instagram uh
you're not going to be able to see these
slides but don't worry I will be reading
these verses so
so fear not the most powerful testimony
um
let's see here okay
so there I am
that those are pictures of me
uh this is when we're in the the the
hip-hop group uh known as the Boogie
monsters
um this is
um right around the time of my
conversion
but I want to let you know what led me
to this my life up to this point
uh before I was converted
so I was not brought up as a Christian
and I'm not sharing my testimonies so I
know many of you have heard my testimony
but that's not what we're going to be
talking about today I'm just kind of
giving you a little bit of backdrop
I wasn't brought up as a Christian I
wasn't brought up in any particular uh
religion or belief system
but
I had a question I always had a question
about what is truth what is the truth
um growing up in New York I was born in
Jamaica grew up in New York and
um growing up in New York
um you run into a lot of people who are
um always sharing right their religious
beliefs Five Percenters Nation of Islam
all kinds of different uh uh belief
systems all kinds of different uh uh um
philosophies
this is what truth is and this is why
you need to follow this particular
belief system so for me growing up I was
always skeptical of religion altogether
why because
if there was such a thing as truth
how come everybody didn't know what this
truth was if there was such a thing as
truth
how come people were
all these different religions
you have Islam you have Buddhism you
have Hindus and you got all you got
Christianity and within Christianity
itself you have hundreds of different
denominations and non-denominational
churches
how could anyone claim
to have the truth I thought it was just
like a ridiculous claim to make and so I
could actually understand
the agnostic or atheistic position you
know how can we I would say more the
agnostic position how can we even know
that there is a God and if there is a
God which God
which God
now put a one in the chat if you can
resonate with what I'm saying right now
because I want you to know I'm not
coming from this from a biased position
in the sense of I was born into this and
I grew up in this and this is what I've
always believed no no no no I was very
skeptical not just of the Bible but of
all religion
everything
so
there came a point where uh myself my my
younger brother uh and a couple of our
friends we we ended up getting a record
deal and in this record deal we were
assigned to a to a million dollar
contract just under a million dollar
contract with Emi records and for those
of you who may be watching this for the
first time or hearing about this for the
first time hearing about me for the
first time you might be wondering if you
were signed to a million dollar contract
with Emi records what are you doing here
right now preaching
foreign
let me tell you something Beloved the
truth is more precious than a million
dollars
the truth is more precious than anything
this war has to offer Fame no it it's
more precious than all of that so if you
want to know
how are you sitting here right now if
you had a record deal if you you know
had an eighth album contract in the
hip-hop industry how why are you sitting
here right now that's why because I can
say with absolute conviction that I
found the truth
now again I understand your skepticism
if you're skeptical if you're watching
this you're you know I'm gonna give this
guy a shot and hear what he's hear what
he's saying I understand the skepticism
but I I laid out that Foundation just so
that you can know that I think that I
used to think how you thought how you're
thinking right now how can we know the
truth all these different religions all
these different beliefs everyone
claiming this is the truth this is the
way how can you actually know what is
truth and how can you be so confident
confident enough to walk away from a
million dollars and beloved that was
just the initial contract that's not
talking about the fame that was to come
afterward and all that no no no that's
just the initial contract
how were you willing to walk away from
that you might ask
because the truth is more precious let
me tell you I walked away from that
as a person who was skeptical of all
religion see
I was My Philosophy was like this look
people are what they are because they
were born into that thing
if you live in America the dominant
religion is Christianity so everybody's
going to be like yeah I'm a Christian
but you know you why are you about this
why are you a Methodist why are you a
Catholic why
why are you about this and not a
Catholic why are you a Methodist and not
Presbyterian why it's because y'all are
brought up like that it's because
you maybe just went eeny meeny miny mo
and picked something
just to be safe just in case
God is real
all these different belief systems so
you might be asking pastor with with
that with that mentality what led you
to where you are right now let me tell
you let me go back to the screen
it was
one night
one night that changed everything for me
it was the night that I heard the most
powerful testimony now the title of this
message is the most powerful testimony
and you may have thought just now that I
was going to be giving you my testimony
I am not going to be giving you my
testimony I'm going to be giving you
somebody else's testimony but it was the
most powerful testimony
that I had ever heard
are y'all with me so far
this testimony changed everything for me
so
let's let's begin to break this down by
the way I'm not giving you the testimony
yet I I still got to set you up so let's
go to the screen and I want you to see
all the different possibilities when it
comes to religion if we can get this up
on the screen
there is there is Islam
there is Hinduism there is Buddhism
there is the Hebrew Israelites there the
Jehovah's Witnesses they're the Mormons
um there's mysticism
there's Catholicism
like we can continue we can go down the
list right of all these different belief
systems including agnosticism which says
how can we we don't know that there is a
God including atheism which says I don't
believe in God I I know there is no God
there's the New Age movement how can we
how do we maneuver ourselves through all
these beliefs
see each one of these religions or
non-religions makes a claim
they make a claim
um they are testifying of something put
that word in the chat for me please
testify if you can they are testifying
of something
what are they they're giving a testimony
they're saying listen
um um you need to believe me
because I am good
you need to believe us because we are
telling you the truth that's what they
are testifying that's their testimony uh
uh some people come saying hey you need
to believe me because a higher power
sent me or you need to believe me
because I had a special encounter with
God or some higher power so there are
many claims right or many testimonies
from these different religions saying
this is why
you should follow me are y'all with me
so far
so as we are trying to determine uh um
should I become a Muslim should I become
a Hebrew Israelite should I become a
Christian and if so should I become a
Baptist or a Methodist should I become
uh uh an atheist should I become an
adult what should I be
what you're doing
maybe you didn't even realize this but
what you're doing is you're actually
looking and listening to the testimony
of these different belief systems put a
one in the chat if you're following
what is a testimony and it looks like
our slides may not be working because
they're not coming up on the screen so
not only Instagram are you unable to see
these slides but I guess YouTube and
Facebook y'all not gonna be able to see
these slides but don't worry I will make
these slides available and they're going
to be placed in the chat
uh once this video goes goes um
goes Fully live okay so what is a
testimony
a testimony ah
there we go I spoke too soon
uh there we go a testimony is a solemn
declaration usually made orally by a
witness under oath in response to an
interrogation by a lawyer or
unauthorized public official so that's
the first definition of a testimony
a solemn declaration usually made orally
by a witness under oath in response to
interrogation by a lawyer or authorized
public official so in this case
when we are searching for the testimony
of a particular religion
we that religion is under interrogation
we are interrogating that religion we
are interrogating the founder of that
religion we're asking why should I
believe you does that make sense
is that does that sound
like a like a fair approach thus far
when someone comes to you and says you
should be a Muslim what do you do you're
well what's the testimony what is your
what is your evidence you're
interrogating the system or the founder
of the system to to to know whether the
testimony is true or not
and when we find that the testimony is
not true if we find the testimonies not
true then we know yeah I'm not following
that why because it's not true
here's a second definition
of a testimony it is first-hand
authentication of a fact
right so when a witness is called and
they give testimony they are giving
first hand authentication of a fact they
saw it they were there
they they they are eyewitnesses they
have evidence that the thing is true
because they saw it themselves so again
when we are looking and listening for
the various religious beliefs we are
searching for Testimony number one
what do you have to say for yourself
what's your testimony why I should
believe this system or why I should
follow you and number two you're looking
for first-hand
authentication of a fact the witness
should be able to tell you something
firsthand
are y'all with me so far
it is an interrogation into the truth
that's what we're doing we're
interrogating all these claims of this
is truth and this is truth and this is
truth we're interrogating so what does
it mean to interrogate it means to ask
questions of someone especially a
suspect or a prisoner closely
aggressively or formally
so when you're interrogating you're
closely investigating the claims of said
religion most atheists are atheists
because after investigating the claims
of this religion and that religion and
that religion they say your testimonies
are false therefore I'm not following I
have no reason to believe
are y'all with me so far
a Muslim who becomes a Muslim is one who
has heard a a apparent evidence from the
Quran and believes that evidence and
says therefore I'm a Muslim it's an
interrogation you're asking questions
you're asking questions uh uh uh of
someone in a close sometimes aggressive
or formally or formal manner
so the search for truth is an
interrogation and the question is very
simple is the testimony true that's the
question
is the testimony true Islam is your
testimony true Hebrew Israelites is your
testimony true Five Percenters is your
testimony true our Mormons is your
rastafarianism is your testimony true if
we find no truth in these testimonies
then we have a problem maybe not a
problem we can walk away and say hey
none of this is true all of it is made
up
and I want you to realize that every one
of these religions has a testimony now
now why am I bringing this up I'm
setting the foundation because I want
you to understand something very
important here that the Bible tells us
that Jesus Christ has a testimony
put a one in the chat
put a one in the chat if you understand
what I'm saying here Jesus Christ
has a testimony Revelation 12 17 the
Bible says the dragon was Wrath with the
woman and went to make war with the
remnant of a seed which keep the
Commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus Christ so again
everyone just put a one in the chat if
you understand you may not agree with
the testimony of Jesus Christ you may
not even understand the testimony of
Jesus Christ but yes he has a testimony
according to the scripture
which
to be fair to the atheists for all for
all that you you might believe right now
the scriptures just made a book it's a
made of book with false testimony that's
what you may think
but but just for the sake of our message
today just looking at the scripture for
those of you who are skeptical of the
Bible I understand but but I need to
show you something very very important
the Bible lets us know here that Jesus
Christ has a testimony
you see it right there on the screen the
testimony of Jesus Christ so we might
ask then what is Jesus's testimony what
is his claim
are y'all good with that
what is his claim what is his testimony
as to why we should believe him
when someone testifies they're
testifying to bring something to light
they're testifying saying you need to
believe what I saw you need to believe
me
should we believe Jesus or should we
believe somebody else
should we believe Jesus Through The Eyes
of the Baptist so we believe Jesus
Through The Eyes of the Hebrew
Israelites should we believe Jesus
Through The Eyes of the Mormon or the
Jehovah's Witness or the Catholic or the
Methodist or the Adventist who should we
believe who has the testimony of Jesus
the true testimony of Jesus if in fact
his testimony is true
so let's break this down y'all because
the testimony of Jesus is something very
specific in Revelation 19 verse 10 the
Bible says and I fill at his feet to
worship him and he said unto me see the
bow do it not I am my fellow servant of
thy Brethren that have the testimony of
Jesus worship God for the testimony of
Jesus is what
what is the testimony of Jesus according
to the verse
the testimony of Jesus is the spirit of
Prophecy
put a one in the chat if you understand
understand that Instagram you're
watching put that one in the chat if you
understand that the testimony of Jesus
is the spirit of Prophecy now we need to
break this down because I know many of
you have read this verse before and I
know what you're thinking right now
but I'm gonna take you in a different
direction
let me see if I can rephrase this for
you
imagine Jesus you know you you go to you
go to to uh
um you know Muhammad what's your
testimony or my testimony is and he
tells you in a nutshell this is what I'm
going to use for my testimony all right
what about your what are you gonna okay
for me I'm gonna use this for my
testimony okay nationally Islam all
right Hindus what are you going to use
for your well for my testimony we're
gonna use it so Jesus's test the thing
that Jesus says this is my testimony
as to why you should believe me he says
it's prophecy
put a one in the chat if you understand
the point that I just made
what I'm going to share
in an effort to get you to believe me to
believe who I am is uh from my testimony
I'm gonna share prophecy
that's my thing
prophecy
let's go back to the screen
so Jesus's testimony
is the spirit of Prophecy
and and watch this the spirit of
Prophecy is what Jesus is going to
testify that's his testimony it's a
spirit of Prophecy and he's testifying
remember when you testify you're
supposed to be testifying of facts
but in order to testify come back I need
y'all to come back and see me for this
in order to testify of something
you have to be are y'all come come on
come you have to have
first hand account
you have to be an eyewitness
now watch this guys if Jesus is saying
Hey My My Testimony is going to be the
spirit of Prophecy so I'm going to be
testifying to you about prophecy that's
the fact okay well how are you going to
do that watch this
thank you
if Jesus is testifying of Prophecy I
need you to understand prophecy is by
definition
that which has not yet occurred put a
one in the chat if you understand what I
just said prophecy is by definition
that which has not yet occurred so if
Jesus is saying I'm going to testify of
this as a fact
I'm going to testify of this as a fact
because that's what Witnesses are called
to do they're called to witness of a
fact so if Jesus says I'm my testimony
is prophecy
which is something that has not yet
happened but I'm going to testify of it
as a fact
how in the world you're going to do that
Jesus
you see Beloved the only way Jesus could
testify of something that is yet future
and testified as a fact
before the fact occurs means that he is
claiming Divinity y'all put one in the
chat put a one in the chat if you
understand this point that I'm making
right here I need y'all to really follow
this y'all
he says
I'm gonna testify of something that has
not yet happened
laughs
now I want y'all to understand something
how many of you like you know how many
of you remember when you were kids and
you would have like a show and tell
you know show and tell you know first
grade second grade Show and Tell third
grade fourth grade so and tell
and you know you probably like had your
your little you know thing that you're
gonna show and then and then that one
kid comes to the class and the thing
that he shows and tells is just like
everybody's mind is blown like wait what
so I I need you to catch this okay
Jesus said Jesus sets himself aside from
every other claim
every religion every founder of every
relay he sets himself aside by saying
hey my testimony is going to be about
things that have not yet happened
look at the screen look at what Jesus
himself said in John 13 verse 19 Jesus
said now I tell you before it come to
pass that when it come to pass you may
believe that I am he
yo is that is that combat is that deep
y'all
Jesus says look here's how I'm going to
get you to believe the way I'm going to
get you to believe is I'm going to tell
you something that has not yet happened
and when it happens you will have no
choice but to believe that I'm he
because you see I need you to understand
that
Humanity does not have access to the
Future
created beings do not have access to the
only someone who is divine can have
access to the Future
hold that thought just just put that
thought in the back of your mind for a
moment and I want you to come back to
the screen I want you to notice what
Jesus says in John 14 verse 29 and I
want to show you how the Bible lays out
this challenge
John 14 29 Jesus again says this and now
I have told you before it come to pass
that when it has come to pass you might
what believe
believe
the Bible is full of this listen all
created beings have access to past facts
present facts and future facts based on
past and present facts so come back to
the screen
if I say to you hey guys
I know for a fact that five days from
now the sun will be shining there may be
clouds in the sky but the sun will be
shining you guys that's nothing that's
nothing deep that's not a profound
statement why am I so sure that the sun
will be shining five days from now ten
days from now 20 days from now it's
because that that statement is based off
of past fact are y'all with me
so there are things that I can look in
the past and determine Yep this is going
to happen if I take this and drop it I'm
not I'm not prophesying by saying it's
going to fall I know from experience
it's going to fall that's not prophecy
are y'all with me
so genuine prophecy is something that
cannot be made if it exists it's
something that cannot be made up
and by the way the reason why many
Skeptics turn away from prophecy which
they do is because the things they have
heard are totally false and bogus
understandings of Prophecy
and they see through it and they're like
yeah not not going for that
are you with me so far
so so we're not looking for that's right
claim we're not looking for historical
patterns where we can look at the past
and you know guess the future we're not
looking at scientific patterns prophecy
is not based on past history or science
it is totally outside the realm
of human control
so if there is a being that knows the
future that has access to the future we
can conclude safely that that there is
such a thing as God there is a Divine
being outside of our existence
that knows and understands things we
have no idea about things we do not
so I hope this is fair so far
let's go back to the screen only a
Divine being could have access to Future
facts unconnected to past or present
detail
right
that's pretty simple
that's pretty straightforward
notice what Isaiah 41 verses 22 and 23
say and I want you to note how often God
himself lays out this test look at what
he says let them bring them forth and
he's talking about he was talking to
Israel at this time and saying look
Israel y'all are worshiping other gods
bring these Gods these gods that you
believe exist bring them all together
notice what he says
and show us what shall happen let them
show the former things what they be that
we may consider them and know the latter
end of them or declare us things for to
come so the things that ought to come
Hereafter that we may know that you are
Gods yea do good or evil that we may be
dismayed and behold it together what
he's saying is this listen
call all your Gods together bring all
your religions together this is God's
challenge himself if this God exists I
get you atheist I'm following how you
know God so let's just say that this
will fit you know y'all believe that you
believe there's a fairy tale God the
Bible is fairy tale but not what this
quote-unquote fairy tale book says it
says call all your gods and all your
religious religions together and let the
founder of those religions let the one
who claims to be God tell the future and
if he can do that let him be God
that's God's Own test now I'm going to
tell you I'm going to show you in a
moment that this is a test that even
atheists accept they see the genuine
nature of this claim of this test
listen we're gonna keep on Isaiah 44
verse 6.
thus say the Lord the king of Israel and
his Redeemer the Lord of hosts I am the
first and I am the last and beside me
there is no God and who is I shall call
and shall declare it and set it in order
for me since I pointed the ancient
people and the things that are coming
and shall come let them show unto them
again God is challenging all the other
God so to speak
he's challenging Humanity to say you
believe in this God you believe in this
religion you believe in this thing you
believe in this holy book let that book
let that God tell you what's coming in
the future and if he can do that then
let him be God let him accurately
predict let him show that he not only
has access to past like everybody else
not only has access to the present like
everybody else but unlike anybody else
he has access to the Future
foreign
46 verse 9 and 10. remember the former
things of old for I am God and there is
none else I am God and there is none
like me declaring the end from the
beginning and from ancient times the
things that are not yet done saying my
counsel shall stand and I will do all my
pleasure once again God declaring the
same thing Isaiah 48 verse 5.
I have even from the beginning declared
it to be before it came to pass I showed
it to thee lest thou shall say my idol
has done them and my Graven image and my
molten image has commanded them so here
you see that God is clearly laying out
this singular challenge
prophecy
that's the testimony
that's the thing he's saying none of
these other religions yes the Battle of
the Gods the Battle of the Gods you
believe in this God you believe God
doesn't exist I'm going to Demi I'm
going to give you a testimony and let me
tell you beloved this is the testimony
of Jesus and this is what I mean by the
most powerful testimony the most
powerful testimony I have ever heard is
the testimony of Jesus Christ that's
what led me to walk away from a contract
that's what led me to walk away from
Fame that's what led me to walk away
from everything the world has to offer
it was the testimony of Jesus Christ
which is the spirit of Prophecy come
back to the screen with me
Isaiah 48 verse 3 I have declared the
former things from the beginning and
they went forth out of my mouth I showed
them I did them suddenly and they came
to pass John 21 24 this is a disciple
which testified of these things and
wrote these things and we know that his
testimony is true I just want you to
focus on that last part there we know
that his testimony is true and I just
want to I just want to separate this
from a moment and I'm just looking at
that last part those last uh four words
his testimony is true when we look for a
testimony we're trying to find out one
thing and one thing only is the
testimony
true
is the testimony
all right
listen to this
if
if Jesus's testimony of facts before
they become facts not based on any past
or present information available is true
then we ought to believe him so come
back to come back to me and let me let
me see make sure you catch this point
if the if the testimony of Jesus is true
should we then believe him
yes or no
if the testimony of Hinduism is true
if the testimony of Buddhism of Buddhism
is true if the testimony of of of of of
the Nation of Islam is true if the
testimony of of of this religion or that
religion or that if the if the testimony
is true and listen to me
true
all right if I say to you
this is a glass
now I want you to follow me as a prophet
I got a question for you
is it true that this is a glass
yes it is true
is this truth that this is a glass
enough to convict you that I am
a prophet and that you should follow me
the answer is
no
see here's what what I'm trying to say
for me as a skeptic of religion it
wasn't enough for someone to say you
know be kind to your neighbor I believe
that I think that's a true statement I
think one should be kind to their
neighbor but anybody can say be kind to
your neighbor
if someone says you know what you
shouldn't eat these kind of foods
because you know it's bad for your
health
hey I might believe and be like okay
that's true that's not that doesn't give
me a legitimate reason to suddenly
believe that your religion is divine
that your religion is Supernatural are
you catching what I'm saying
so the significance of Jesus saying hey
my testimony is not going to be
you should obey me because I am God or
this you know you should live life this
way and do what I say you should be kind
not even you should love he says I'm
going to do something that will let you
know that no other being could do
that no other religion can claim
so that the things that I do speak to
you I want you to eat this way I want
you to live this way I now you're gonna
do them because you believe that I am
you believe that I exist you believe
that I am God and so now now that I've
caught your attention there now when I
tell you so I want you to do this and I
want you to do this and I want you to do
this you're going to believe you're
going to do it
are you catching what I'm saying
oh
so I know what some Skeptics are saying
even right now
you're like
well if you're going to talk about
prophecy like you know someone just put
in the chat and there's a good prophecy
someone just put in the chat you know
Jesus said he was going to die and you
know be raising it on the third day and
it happened you know what the skeptic
says to that the skeptic says come on
you guys
this you're pulling evidence from the
same book that is making the claim
how do you know this wasn't written in
after the fact
you're you're using the Bible
to try to verify you're using events in
the Bible to try to verify the Bible
what kind of sense does that make that's
circular reasoning and listen even
though I believe that those prophecies
are genuine I agree with the skeptic it
it doesn't make sense for to a
non-believer to use
evidence in the Bible
to try to back up
the fact that the try to back up the
idea that the Bible is true
that would be considered circular
reasoning and I want to I want to let
you know something God knows that that's
why God chose the form of testimony that
he chose
so come I need to come back genuine
prophecy that's what we're talking about
we're not talking about prophecy that
can be manipulated we're talking about
genuine prophecy and I want to I want to
read something to you uh this is from a
book by Guy P Harrison who is a an
atheist I believe
um either agnostic or atheist but I
think he's an atheist
he wrote a book called 50 reasons people
give for believing in a God that was the
name of the book 50 reasons people give
for believing unto God and he goes down
the list just kind of lambasting and and
just you know uh uh uh destroying these
arguments of why people believe in God
so can you come back to the screen just
come back to me just for a moment so
here's a typical example
I believe in God because he changed my
life
I used to be a drug addict and when I
gave my life to the Lord and I became a
Christian my life was changed and the
skeptic says
well I know Muslims whose lives were
changed when they became serious Muslims
and I knew I know I know Buddhists whose
lives were changed when when they
embraced that religion how does that
demonstrate that your God is real that
your God is truth is the true God
if there is a God or you're following me
are you understanding what I'm saying
so so in this book he is laying out he's
laying out the arguments that he usually
hears about why you should believe in
God oh he changed my life oh well look
look at nature you should be able to
tell that there's okay there's a real
God but who is the real God if there's a
real God who is the real God
he's going on the list and making all
these arguments none that I want you to
notice what he says here which is
absolutely
mind-blowing check this out let's go
back to the screen
so here's what he says under the section
entitled ancient prophecies prove my God
exists so this is one of the 50
arguments I think it was argument like
number 48 or something like that he says
under the section entitled ancient
prophecies prove my God exists here's
what Harrison writes he says like most
AC like most atheists
I'm not insane I don't like pain believe
me I don't want to suffer in anyone's
hell for all eternity
if there was just one precise and
detailed prediction that came true and
could be explained as the work of a God
no matter if it were of in the Bible the
Quran the Torah the Gita the Dianetics
David caresses uh diary and so on I
would not ignore it or deny it
if gods are real
and they really want to impress all of
us with their prophecies then why don't
they make the prediction obvious to
everyone including well-meaning Skeptics
imagine for example if a holy book was
discovered in the 1990s and contained
the following ancient prophecy confirmed
to have been written down more than 3000
years ago in a year to be called 1969 by
the people of Tomorrow two men named
kneeling Buzz will Ascend to the moon
and walk upon its surface a metallic
bird named Eagle will serve as their
Chariot and they will do a thing called
Eva while wearing white
upon their heads will be large sturdy
hats Shields of gold will protect their
eyes the people of Earth will cheer them
on from afar upon the return of the two
men plus one named Michael they will
shout out the name Apollo as the Lord
saw their flag standing in the Stillness
of the Loon escapes of the lunar
Landscapes he did smile
that's the end of the so-called prophecy
now if a Believer can show me a prophecy
with that kind of detail I'm on board
with their religion sign me up put that
in the chat for me please
just put those words in a chat sign me
up this is coming from an atheist and I
want you to understand how reasonable
his argument is
and yet there's a flaw in the argument
because
if a prophecy were that plain
and then it were fulfilled the argument
from the skeptic would be while the
argument the prophecy was too plain and
people wanted to fulfill that prophecy
so there was human interaction to
attempt to fulfill that prophecy and
that's why it was fulfilled which is
totally reasonable
you put out something that's that that
plane and it's totally reasonable for a
group of people to say hey let's try to
fulfill this thing and then it's not
divinely fulfilled it's fulfilled based
upon human Ingenuity and human attempts
Etc
he finishes the court by saying this
but such predictions simply do not exist
the ones we have are vague or too easily
explained as events that could have
occurred without the involvement of a
god
I need y'all to understand this
like he's spot on with his approach but
he is dead wrong in his assumption that
there is no prophecy that exists like
this
so
let's go back to the screen and I'm
going to quote another book before we
jump into this what happened to me that
night that changed everything
the book is called what is atheism a
short introduction it's written by
Douglas E Krueger and in his book he
presents the following five criteria to
judge so-called prophecy which he sure
in his own mind does not really exist
here's what he wrote
some criteria are needed in order to
distinguish cases of lucky guesses from
those of true prophecy let us Define a
genuine prophecy as one that satisfies
the following five criteria number one
the prophecy must be clear and it must
contain sufficient detail to make its
fulfillment by a wide variety of
possible events unlikely
number two the event that can fulfill
the prophecy must be unusual or unique
number three the prophecy must be known
to have been made before the event that
is supposed to be its fulfillment
number four the event foretold must not
be of the sort that could be the result
of an educated guess
these are all powerful uh uh uh factors
beloved to determine between a genuine
prophecy if it exists and just so-called
prophecy manipulated prophecy number
five is this
the event that fulfills a prophecy
cannot be staged or the relevant
circumstances manipulated by those aware
of the prophecy in such a way as to
intentionally cause the prophecy to be
fulfilled
all right
I need you to understand that by this
criteria which I think is an excellent
criteria by the way by this criteria
most so-called prophecies from most all
religions in the world fail miserably on
that one test so let's just let's just
bring this all together before we move
into this this one prophecy and we're
gonna we're gonna do this it's not that
complicated
but I just need you to understand for
the skeptical mind
listen
the only thing I'm buying is genuine
prophecy but that doesn't even exist
that's a skeptic argument
if it does exist these are the criteria
let me rephrase that these will be the
criteria that the prophecy must pass to
prove that it is genuine but no prophecy
passes this criteria therefore there's
no genuine prophecy therefore everything
this the Quran says be good you know
whatever whatever any man can say that
any man can come along and say you know
do nice things believe in this God and
you will be saved do this and you'll be
saved any human being can get up today
and write a book and claim that it's
divinely inspired
but no human being has access to the
Future in the way that God has laid out
the challenge
all right
I just want you to check this out on the
screen y'all
see this
all of these religions
fail of any meaningful prophecy
everyone on a minute you see on the
screen and the hundreds of other
religions
none of them
have prophecy
understood
in the way that Jesus's testimony is
given in scripture now I know that some
of you are watching you'll be back no no
what are you talking about we you fill
in the blank we understand prophecy we
got prophecy we got this we got no no no
no no no no
but that's going to be for another study
what I'm about to do right now is simply
show this one point what is it what is
the testimony that I heard that night
that is absent from every other religion
outside the Bible now let me let me just
make a point here
there are many belief systems that claim
to have the Bible as their system as
their Foundation of Truth
but they have totally mixed up the
testimony of Jesus
so that what they claim as prophecy
makes no sense
what they claim as prophecy
is seen by the careful eye as clearly
false prophecy for example Israel is
going to become a nation again in 1948
that's not in the Bible y'all
and yet teachings like this and many
others are are are are pushed out there
in the public and Skeptics who know
better and understand what's the verse
you're using to to demonstrate this yeah
that doesn't say that at all
and while you know the the the the guy
who believes or lady who believes their
religion May believe that when you test
it out in a in a unbiased way
that's not prophecy no that's not
prophecy no what you thought was prophet
what's your teacher that's not prophecy
Left Behind perfect example
so what is it that I heard that night
let's go to the screen what is it that I
heard that night the testimony I heard
that night the testimony of Jesus Christ
what is that testimony well
we're gonna go
to the Book of Daniel chapter 2.
that night
me and my friends
we were in New York City New York
Brooklyn New York no Queens I'm sorry
Queens New York
all hanging out this night
and
something miraculous happened
a friend of ours had brought a friend of
his to our house and we ended up talking
about the Bible just out of the blue the
conversation just kind of came up and
the the young man that talked about the
Bible with us
broke down something that absolutely
blew my mind
and to this day
to this day blows my mind
so come on what he shared with me was
Daniel chapter two
so
a little bit of backdrop about the Book
of Daniel
Skeptics believe that the Book of Daniel
was written in the second century BC
right so just uh you know one or two
centuries before Jesus
um before
Jesus birth
uh those who believe in the validity of
the Book of Daniel believe that the book
was written in the 6th Century BC so if
you even go to Wikipedia you'll see
Wikipedia say this The Book of Daniel is
a second century BC a Biblical
apocalypse with a sixth Century BC
setting so Wikipedia is trying to say
that yeah the Book of Daniel was really
written in the second century and the
reason why come back to the screen for a
moment the reason why they are saying
the Book of Daniel was written in the
second century
is because they're saying there is no
way that the events that were foretold
in the Book of Daniel could have
happened so it's not Divine what
happened is that the book was written
much later than it claims to have been
written
it's not the sixth Century it's the
second century because if it was a sixth
Century there is no explanation for how
Daniel knew allegedly knew what he wrote
what he prophesied how was Daniel going
to know that except the The God Who he
claimed gave him that that prophecy is
real so Skeptics say nah the book was
written in the second century right just
before the rise of the Roman Empire
so let's go back to the Book of Daniel
Daniel chapter 2.
and we're going to begin reading from
verse one in the second year of the
reign of Nebuchadnezzar nebuchadne has a
dream the dreams were with his Spirit
was troubled and his sleep break from
him then the king commanded to call The
Magicians and the astrologers and the
sorcerers and the Chaldeans for to show
the king his dream so they came and
stood before the king and the King said
unto them I have dreamed a dream and my
spirit was troubled to know the dream
then spayed the Chaldeans to the king in
Syriac O King live forever tell thy
servants to dream and we will show the
interpretation the king answered and
said to the Chaldeans the thing is gone
from me and if he will not make known
unto me the dream with the
interpretation thereof you shall be cut
in pieces and your houses shall be made
a dunghill but if you show the dream and
the interpretation thereof then
therefore you saw receive of me gifts
and rewards and great honor therefore
show me the dream and the interpretation
thereof now I want y'all to understand
this
what's happening in this dream what's
happening in this chapter is this
Nebuchadnezzar who is not a believer in
God so very important Point here he's
not a believer in God he's a king of
Babylon he has a dream he can't remember
the dream he wakes up and he's super
troubled but he can't remember the dream
so he calls in his magicians and his
Sorcerers and all those who claim to
have this connection with all these
other gods and he's like hey I drink the
dream but I can't remember what the
dream is so I need you to tell me what
the dream is and then tell me what the
dream means and they're like we can't do
that
and he's like what do you mean you can't
do that I thought I thought you had
connection with the Gods
you're worshiping I thought you had
truth
they're like we can't do that so he's
threatens them and look if y'all don't
you know tell me what I dreamed and what
the dream means I'm gonna kill you
let's keep going verse five they're like
tell us a dream and then we'll tell you
so they're trying to get some kind of
footing at least try to remember your
dream he's like I can't remember the
dream the king answered and said to the
Chaldeans the thing is gone for me
if you if you will not make an honest
with me the dream no no I'm sorry we
read that verse 7.
they answered again and said let the
King show his servants a dream and we
will show the interpretation of it the
king answered and said I know of a
certainty that you would gain the time
because you see the thing is gone from
me in other words the king is realizing
that he's been bamboozled the king is
realizing that the testimony of these
guys has been false
verse 9 but if you will not make known
unto me the dream there is but one
decree for you for you have prepared
lying and corrupt words to speak before
me till the time be changed therefore
tell me the dream and I shall know that
you can show me the interpretation
thereof verse 10. the Chaldeans answered
before the king and said there is not a
man upon the Earth that can show the
king's matter therefore there is no King
Lord nor ruler that adds such a thing at
any magician or astrologer or Chaldean
and it is a rare thing that the king
requires and there is none other that
can show it before the king except the
gods whose dwelling is not in the flesh
now I want y'all to come back to the
screen for a second I need y'all to see
this
even these magicians are like what
you're asking is impossible
how are we supposed to know what is
inside the human heart what is inside
the human mind much less tell you what
the dream means and we're going to see
this is a prophetic dream they can't do
it they're like only now you know they
don't know the god of heaven so their
response is only the gods can do that
and God says no no no no the gods can't
do that
because what you claim to be Gods
they're not Gods only God can do that
all right so for some of the Skeptics
watching this right now you're saying
yeah but this is all still a bunch of
fairy tales this is a story you're
trying to use a story in the Bible to
confirm the Bible no I'm not doing that
I'm not doing that let me show you come
follow me follow me
so here's where we're introduced to
these characters Daniel Shadrach Meshach
and Abednego they are Hebrews and they
hear about this decree to kill all The
Magicians and wise men and they're like
hold on they're they're captives in in
in Babylon right now so they say hold on
because the death decree involves them
they're like hey let us go pray to our
God
give us a night let's go pray to our God
and so here's what the Bible says verse
17 picking up then Daniel went to his
house and made the thing known to
hananiah Michelle and Azariah his
companions also known as Shadrach
Meshach and Abednego
that they will desire the mercies of the
god of Heaven concerning the secret that
Daniel and his wise and his fellows
should not perish with the rest of the
wise men of Babylon then was the secret
revealed unto Daniel in the night vision
then Daniel blessed the god of Heaven
verse 20. Daniel answered and said
blessed be the name of God forever and
ever for wisdom and might are his and he
changes the times and the seasons and
removeth kings and Sabbath of Kings he
giveth wisdom unto the wise and
knowledge to them that no understanding
he revealed the deep and secret things
he knows what is in darkness and the
light dwells in them in other words
Daniel is saying listen Our God knows
what nobody else knows
now if I'm going to follow a God if I'm
going to follow someone who claims to be
divine and you can't show me something
divine
I can tell you the future what reason do
I have to believe that your God is a God
I should follow
what reason do I have to believe because
you said it
because you said he changed your life I
can go to 20 other people for 20 other
religions and they're going to tell me
the same thing this God changed my life
that God stopped me from drinking
all right so notice what Daniel says in
Daniel 2 27 Daniel answered in the
presence of the king now he goes to the
king and said the secret which the King
has demanded cannot the wise men the
astrologers The Magicians the
soothsayers show unto the king let me
add in here
you may as well put all these other
religions
because none of these other religions
have understand prophecy or even have it
as an element it's very broad prophecy
like the world will end one day you guys
anybody can say the world will end one
day
that's not genuine prophecy things are
going to get really bad in the future
that's not genuine prophecy you're gonna
see not in this study but you will see
that when God gives prophecy he give
dates and times and length and
characters involved before they even
come on the scene
nobody no human in and of themselves can
do that
accept God
so watch this watch this exactly Gavin
I'm about to demonstrate why whether the
book was written in the 6th Century or
the second century it has no bearing on
the magnitude of what you are about to
see in Daniel chapter 2.
all right
Daniel 2 verse 7 verse verse verse 8.
but there is a God in heaven that
reveals secrets and make known to the
King Nebuchadnezzar what shall be in the
latter days now pause for a second y'all
Daniel just tells Nebuchadnezzar God is
about to show you what will be in the
last days at the end of time
now look
you go to a psychic today and the psyche
might be like hey next week you're gonna
run into you know a person that you know
that's not real prophecy huh
I remember someone saying when you call
a psychic you know you're trying to find
your future and what they know and then
they ask you for their credit card ask
them
to read your credit card number
I just loved when that when the person
said ask them to read your credit card
number
they're not genuine profits
they don't know
that's a scam that's a real scam
but when God gives prophecy he gives it
on such a level with such Clarity that
there can be no multiple you know ways
it can be seen no no none of that it it
it's it's either gonna hit or if it
doesn't then you know you don't have to
believe in this God
here's what he says Daniel 2 28.
thy dream and the visions of thy Head
Upon thy bed are these
as for the O King that thy thoughts came
into thy mind upon thy bed what should
come to pass Hereafter and he that
revealed the secrets maketh known to
thee what shall come to pass Daniel God
showed Daniel what Nebuchadnezzar was
thinking before he went to sleep come on
somebody
before he went to sleep
foreign
here's what he says verse 31 thou O King
sauce and behold a great image this
great image whose brightness was
excellent stood before thee and the form
thereof is terrible the image's head was
a fine gold his chests and arms of
silver his belly in his thighs of brass
his legs of iron his feet part of iron
and part clay
thou saws till that a stone was cut out
without hands which smote the image upon
the feet that were of iron and clay and
break them to Pieces then was the iron
the clay the brass the silver the gold
broken together to be broken to pieces
together and became like the chaff of
the summer aggression floor and the wind
carried them away that no place was
found for them and the stone that smote
the image became a great mountain and
filled the whole earth that's the whole
Vision right there let me say this way
this is the testimony of Jesus
this is Divinity showing Nebuchadnezzar
I'm about to show you what's gonna
happen from this day all the way down to
the very end of time and now it's up to
you and I to interrogate this prophecy
interrogate this testimony
so we gotta question it all right what
are you talking about
Daniel goes on to say this is a dream
and we will tell the interpretation
thereof before the king thou O King are
the King of Kings for God the god of
Heaven has given thee Kingdom power
strength and glory and wheresoever the
children of men dwell the beasts of the
field and the files of the heaven has he
given into thine hand and has made thee
ruler over them all you are this head of
gold so so now when we know that the
head of gold can't represent a car the
head of gold can't represent a cow the
head of gold can't represent money the
head of gold can't represent anything we
want to make it represent for example
like a Nostradamus type of Prophecy
where you can make anything up no we're
we're being told very specifically this
head of gold represents the king of
Babylon and therefore the Empire of
Babylon put Babylon in the chat put
Babylon in the chat if you understand
what I'm saying thus far now
you might think well that's no big deal
if Daniel is living in a time of Babylon
yeah he's going to say the head of gold
of this in his represents Babylon no big
deal Babylon is the reigning Kingdom at
that time
so what's so what's such the big deal
about that
well by the way let's just go to history
and this is from uh Encyclopedia
Britannica so now I want you to see that
I'm going outside the Bible I'm going
outside the Bible to verify what is
inside the Bible I am not going inside
the Bible to verify what is inside I'm
going to secular history to verify what
is prophetically stated in the word of
God now is that fair that that should be
that should be the only way we actually
look at okay is this prophecy genuine
let's see if secular history backs it up
let's see if the thing was written
before the the whole line of events took
place and does Secular history back it
up so here's what we see according to
Encyclopedia Britannica that the
Babylonian captivity also called the
Babylonian exile the forced attention of
Jews in Babylon following the latter
Conquest the latter's conquest of the
kingdom of Judah in 598 slash 7 and
587-6 BCE the Captivity formally ended
in 538 BC when the Persian conqueror of
Babylonia Cyrus the Great gave the Jews
permission to return to Palestine so let
me break this down for you
Daniel says
there's the head of gold there's the
chestnuts of silver there's the billion
thighs of brass there's the legs of iron
so watch this
Daniel says Nebuchadnezzar you and
Babylon the king of Babylon is this head
of gold but then he goes on to say this
he says a second Kingdom will come after
you let's see if we have that on the
screen yep
let me let me go forward let me just
read this real quick so watch this verse
and after thee shall arise another
kingdom inferior to thee and another
third Kingdom of brass which shall bear
rule over all the Earth so we're just
going to come back here so follow me
y'all
Daniel has just told Nebuchadnezzar of
the rise of four kingdoms
the second kingdom is going to overthrow
his kingdom now Daniel is writing at a
time when Babylon is the reigning
Kingdom Babylon is that world Empire and
never and Daniel tells Nebuchadnezzar
you are going to fall to another kingdom
to another kingdom so did that happen in
history
the answer is yes
the middle Persian Empire is the Empire
led by Cyrus the Great
historically speaking this is verifiable
the middle prison Empire overthrew the
Babylon the Babylonian Empire let's go
to the screen
the Battle of Opus was the last major
military engagement between the ahmedian
uh Persian Empire and the neon
neo-babylonian Empire which take which
took place in September 539 BC during
the Persian invasion of Mesopotamia at
the time Babylonia was the last major
power in Western Asia that was not yet
under person control the battle was
fought in or near the Strategic
Riverside City of Opus located north of
the capital city of Babylon
in modern-day Iraq and results in and
resulted in a decisive victory for
Persia shortly afterwards the Babylonian
city of sipar surrendered to Persian
forces who then supposedly entered
Babylon without facing any further
resistance the Persian king Cyrus the
Great was subsequently proclaimed as the
king of Babylon and its subject and its
subject and its subject territories thus
ending its independence and
incorporating the entirety of the Fallen
neo-bablonian empire into the great
Grecian or medo-persian Empire
okay
that's from Wikipedia
so what do we see here
the Bible
predicted the fall of Babylon
and if The Book of Daniel was written in
the 6th Century this is already an
amazing prophecy
but okay let's give you that now the
book was written in the second century
so whoever wrote the book was writing
backward let's take that
let's see what happens next was there a
third Kingdom that overthrew the media
Persian Empire
the answer is yes do y'all know who this
kingdom was it was the kingdom of Greece
here's from the History Channel
how Alexander the Great conquered the
Persian Empire how Alexander the Great
conquered the Persian Empire and the
history is there for us to see again
this is secular history Alexander
defeats the Persians in 331 BC we're not
going to read all about that but it's
there in history no need to to to hammer
this point and to nail this point to the
ground it's history middle Persia fell
to the Grecian Empire
the Bible says according to this
prophecy there was one more Kingdom to
come a fourth Kingdom of iron that would
overthrow that third Kingdom in other
words the Greece and Empire and the
question is did Greece fall to another
Empire and the answer is yes
in 146 BCE the Corinthians were defeated
by the Romans at the Battle of Corinth
taking this Victory as a starting point
Rome soon controlled all of Greece
declaring Corinth the capital of the
Roman of Roman Greece in 44 BCE Julius
Caesar ordered his people to rebuild the
city and his famous Fountain the Romans
decorated the Fountain of pyrene
lavishly painted Lively of frescoes of
Aquatic Life around the walls of the
original Greek Grotto and added an
elaborate facade in the 3rd Century CE
that is still in evidence today so
this fourth kingdom is none other than
the Roman Empire now let me break this
down for you guys just come back to the
screen for a moment and we're almost
done with this prophecy but the powerful
point of this the major point of this is
still is still about to come but I just
wanted to see how fast we're moving
through this prophecy please
please
note this
if the Book of Daniel was written
in the 6th Century BC
then Daniel accurately predicted
600 years of History because Rome came
on the scene 600 years later Daniel
accurately predicted the rise and fall
of four successive nations with absolute
accuracy that is
verifiable by secular history
are y'all with me
are y'all following
this is why Skeptics want to move the
Book of Daniel from the 6th Century to
the second century so they can say no
whoever wrote that already knew about
the fall of Babylon already knew about
the fall of Mita Persia already knew
about the fall of Greece and they knew
that Rome was about to come on the scene
so this is not prophecy okay
so let we got two options here the book
was written in the sixth Century this is
prophecy or we can go with the skeptic
version which is the book was written in
the second century let's go with the
second century version just for a moment
okay
remember if it's sixth Century we
already have
on evidence that cannot be challenged
because it is it is it is backed up by
the testimony of secular history
no other prophecy in any other holy book
has any prophecy on this level none go
search it go search your holy book
you're reading that you are you you have
another religion go search your holy
book
and see if your holy book contains
any prophecy
that spans 600 years naming Nations
telling how many nations would rise how
they would fall and in what order
the prophecy doesn't stop there notice
verse 40 Daniel 2 verse 40. the fourth
Kingdom shall be strong as iron for as
much as I am breaketh in pieces and
subdues all things and as iron that
breaks all these things shall it break
and bruise in pieces
and whereas our sauce defeat and Toes
part of Potter's clay and part of iron
the kingdom shall be divided but there
shall be in it of the strength of the
iron for as much as thou sauce the iron
mixed with myri clay and as the toes of
the feet were part of iron and part of
clay so the kingdom shall be partly
strong and partly broken so come back to
the screen come back to the screen the
prophecy goes on to say this
that fourth Kingdom
the Roman Empire
what would not be overthrown
by another kingdom
no no no no this fourth Kingdom would
break down into smaller kingdoms now I
want y'all to note this okay Instagram
y'all still with me I know I know I can
only be on an hour I don't even know how
long I've been preaching but
are you are you with me all right watch
okay
Daniel could have been like
you know he's on a roll right Babylon
you're going to be over there by another
kingdom the second kingdom is going to
going to be overthrown by Third and the
third is going to be overthrown by a
fourth and he could have very easily
been like and the fourth is going to be
overthrown by a fifth he does not do
that he tells us that the fourth is
going to break down the legs of iron so
head of head of gold first Kingdom
Chester arms of silver of silver second
Kingdom billion thighs of brass third
Kingdom legs of iron fourth Kingdom and
then the fourth kingdom is gonna break
down into smaller kingdoms so my
question is
was Rome overthrown by another Nation
yes or no
what does history tell us
no Rome was not overthrown by another
Nation Rome actually disintegrated from
the inside
and the official date for Rome's
breakdown the disintegration of the
Roman Empire is 476 A.D let's go to the
screen the fall of Rome why when why and
how did Rome fall and you'll see here
right at the bottom of the screen I
don't know if you could see that let me
see see that number right there 476 A.D
476 A.D let me go back and just go to
the next screen in this is from uh the
History Channel in September 476 A.D the
last Roman emperor of the West ramonus
Augustus was deposed by Germanic Prince
called uh autovas Auto vaccar who had
one control of the remnants of the Roman
army of Italy and it goes on to explain
the fall of Rome in 476 A.D what does
this mean come with me y'all listen
carefully
listen and and then we're getting ready
to wrap this up so just give me a few
more moments if you can please okay
listen
if Rome
was in power
when Daniel allegedly wrote the book in
the second Century A.D or they were
getting a BC and they were getting ready
to get into power
Rome doesn't fall until 476 A.D so if
you want to take away that 600 years
from Daniel no no no no we got to start
in the second century BC like around 200
BC instead of 600 BC let's say you we
cut out that 600 years of Prophecy you
still have Daniel from the second
century BC accurately predicting 400
years of history in advance when he says
this fourth Kingdom will not be
overthrown by another kingdom it will
break down
come on y'all
come on now now let's just take that
that 400 year Papa you show me another
Prophecy from another religion
that reaches anywhere near the level of
accuracy
that the Roman Empire would not be
overthrown but would be divided unlike
the other nations that came before it
now watch this y'all because the
prophecy that we just covered a thousand
years of history in one prophecy 600 BC
all the way down to 476 A.D that's
almost a thousand years of Prophecy you
get your holy book of choice you get
your religion of choice and you show me
besides for the
Alex I'm not talking to you you saw me
beside
besides you show me any prophecy in any
other religion any other holy book that
lays out with such accuracy
over a thousand years you want to put
let's choose 600 years let's choose 400
years you tell me bring one to me bring
one one
just one
there isn't
because no other book is like the Bible
none
the reason why many people reject the
Bible is because they don't understand
what it's saying and they say oh look
it's full of contradiction and oh look
there's nothing nothing mysterious about
the book there's nothing Divine about
the book it's because they don't know
the prophecy it's because a version of
Prophecy that they have heard is a
convoluted version of Prophecy one that
cannot be backed up by history and so of
course they're going to be like yeah nah
no no no no no
here you have secular history confirming
what was prophesied in the Bible and
whether you want to choose the sixth
Century date or the second century date
it matters not because we're talking
about a thousand years of history but
watch this y'all
because the prophecy states that these
kingdoms that would be broken down would
not cleave together
let's go back to the screen Daniel we're
almost there y'all we almost done Daniel
2 verse 43 and where's thou sauce the
iron mixed with Maori clay they shall
mingle themselves with the seed of men
but they shall not cleave one to another
even as iron is not mixed with Clay now
we're going to come back to this
question what do you mean they shall
mingle themselves with the seed of men
huh who is they hold on come come so the
kingdom shall be divided we look at what
happened to the Roman Empire and they
were that exact thing happened they were
divided
into smaller Nations into smaller
kingdoms this is history on
and I want you to watch this they have
never reunited as the Bible prophecy
States so what are we now we're in the
year 2023 that means this prophecy is
still going on
come back come back I need y'all to look
at my face with this
we're not talking about
a 1 000 year prophecy
we're talking about
and almost
years of Prophecy
from the kingdom of Babylon 25 plus 100
years later this prophecy is still
accurate and there is nothing like this
in any other holy book or any other
religion in the world
y'all want to know why I left a million
dollars y'all want to know why I walked
away from a contract y'all want to know
why I'm sitting here right now preaching
when I could have been out there in the
world doing music and doing my thing and
having said you want to know why
because of the testimony of Jesus here
this is the testimony of Jesus Jesus
says all right I'm Gonna Give You My
Testimony now all you under God you go
ahead and give your testimony what's
your testimony be good because I am God
well let me give you my testimony
my testimony is I'm the god of the past
and the present and the future
and if I'm the god of the future then
you can trust me with your future
listen to me up
if I told you to trust me and you're
like why should I trust you and I said
look here here's 50 things are going to
happen to you over the next 10 weeks and
you walk away like thinking that guy's
crazy and then those 50 things begin to
happen one after the or one after the
other in the order that I said it would
happen would you begin to believe
anything else I say would you begin to
be first you might have been like he
crazy after you would be like whoa after
the 10th thing after the 15th thing
after the 25th thing yeah I think I'm
gonna start listening
let me put it in terms you might
understand better
if I was able to to tell you hey these
are your lotto numbers for tomorrow and
you won
and I did it again and you won and I did
it again and you won come on how many
hours would I will believe anything you
say
funny how money
can make us have uh make us uh
um
y'all catches but this isn't about money
y'all this is about eternal life
this is about eternal life so if there
is such a thing as eternal life then you
got a serious question on the table
which one of these Gods should I trust
which one of these religions should I
trust should I trust the atheist should
I trust the agnostic should I trust the
Buddhists should I trust the Muslim
should I trust the Christian and if the
Christian which Christian which version
of Christianity listen y'all
those are the real numbers we need to be
focused on
the numbers of eternal life
I wanna I want
to put my eggs in the basket
of the god
that demonstrates that he knows the
future
if you know the future and you've been
there then I'm willing to follow you
so come on watch this y'all 2500 years
of History
but it gets better listen to this
I'm just focusing on this last segment
so remember how we just read they shall
mingle themselves with the seed of men
it almost makes it sound like well who
is the they
who isn't they that shall mingle
themselves with the seed of men what is
that talking about well we're getting
ready to wrap this up here
who is the they
well
they
whoever they are it's got to be men too
this is not something Supernatural
that's happening whatever this prophecy
is talking about they shall mingle
themselves with the seed of men it's got
to be significant it's got and when we
go back what's interesting is when we go
back to the Book of Genesis chapter 3
verse 15.
when Adam and Eve sinned this is what
God said to them he came to them the
serpent was right there in the garden
and here's what he said I will put
enmity between thee and the woman
between thy seed and her seed it shall
bruise thy head and thou shall lose his
heel he sung to the devil to The Serpent
and he's talking to Adam and Eve
and he said I'm gonna put enmity between
your seed Adam and Eve and your seed
serpent let me ask a question what does
it mean the serpent seed what do you
think the Bible means by the serpent
seed
is the devil having babies
you can let's let's come back from on
the screen is the devil having babies
does the devil have offspring
no that's not what God is talking about
the devil's seed are the devil's
children spiritually symbolically the
wicked
the righteous would be Adam and Eve's
seed their offspring the righteous God
has said I'm gonna put enmity between
those who follow Satan and those who
will ultimately follow me because of
course Adam and Eve were forgiven they
had to sacrifice so God is saying I'm
gonna put enmity division between your
seed
and the seat of the serpent
now why is that significant
because this the seed of the righteous
is the one through who is this the line
through which the Messiah would come
now I want you to follow this because
shortly after this event in Genesis
chapter six we find something very
interesting
remember God said I'm going to make it
so that your seed and the seed of the
wicked don't mix like that's not that's
what I'm gonna I'm going to put enmity
so that you guys understand you know
those who follow Satan are not to mingle
with those who follow me
but in Genesis 6 it says this and it
came to pass when men began to multiply
on the face of the Earth and daughters
were born unto them
that the sons of God saw the daughters
of men that they were fair and they took
them wise of which they all chose and
there were giants in those in the earth
in those days and also after that the
sons of God came in unto the daughters
of men and they bear children to them
they became same Mighty Men which were
over now were old were old or old I'm
sorry men of renowned
and God saw that the wickedness of man
was great in the earth and that every
imagination of the thoughts of his heart
was only evil continually so watch this
What's Happening Here Is Not Angels
mingling with the sons of God are not
the angels that are mingled with men
it's the children of Seth
the righteous line mingling with the
seed of men in other words it is the
mingling of the righteous and the wicked
that brings about the condition we see
in Genesis 6 12.
same chapter it says and God looked upon
the Earth and behold it was corrupt for
All Flesh had corrupted his way upon the
Earth and God said unto Noah the end of
All Flesh is come before me for the
Earth is filled with violence through
them and behold I will destroy them with
the Earth so watch this y'all it was the
mingling
of the professed righteous with the
wicked that led to the first destruction
of the world
did y'all catch that
it was the mingling of the right to seed
with the corrupt seed of men that led to
the destruction of the World by water
look at what the Bible says just so that
you know we are the Son of God John 3 1
behold what manner of love the father
has bestowed upon us that we should be
called the sons of God therefore the
world knows us not because it knew him
not beloved now are we the Son of God
and it does not yet appear we shall be
but we do know that when we shall appear
we shall be like him for we shall see
him as he is so the Bible clearly tells
us that the righteous are called the
sons of God it was what was happening in
the days before the flood is that
the righteous line began to mingle with
the wicked line with the Sons and
Daughters of Cain and that is what led
to widespread corruption
are y'all with me
Not Angels the Bible clearly tells us
Jesus says look angels Don't reproduce
so these are not Angels these are the
Righteous and the wicked mingling why am
I sharing this with you because watch
this y'all go back to the screen
remember what we have happening at the
very end of the image in Daniel 2 we
have iron mingling with Clay we're
getting ready to wrap this up I promise
you look
what does the clay represent in the
Bible
the Bible says in Isaiah 64 verse 8 but
now O Lord Thou Art Our Father we are
the clay and thou are Potter and we are
all the work of thine hand Isaiah 64 8
rather iron the Bible says represents
this because I knew that thou art
obstinate and thy neck is an iron sinew
and thy brow brass Isaiah 48 4. come
back come back
what the prophecy is stating here listen
to this y'all what the prophecy is
stating here is that not only would Rome
disintegrates
but what would happen out of the
disintegration of Rome is that they
would arise this iron and Clay element
this element of of the professed people
of God claiming God would begin to
mingle with the iron to begin to make in
other words it would almost be like some
kind of a church
state
entity
rising out of Rome
and it is this
very mingling of church with world
church with state that would bring about
the coming of Jesus The Rock in Daniel
chapter 2 that destroys the image on the
feet it is the just as the mingling of
the righteous and the wicked brought
about the flood
the first destruction of the world
so this mingling of Christianity
with
governments
would be one of the final things that
happened before that stone cut out
without hands destroys the image on its
feet so watch this y'all what was it
that rose out of the Roman Empire after
it fell what was the iron and clay
that mingled with the seed of men
come on y'all it was the Church of the
Dark Ages it was Catholicism it was the
paper scene
come back with me to the screen
I just wanted we're just using history
secular history to demonstrate what
we're talking about listen to what it
says this is from worldhistory.us
the Roman Catholic Church sprung from a
decaying Roman Empire and promoted
health and stability in a medieval
Europe torn by War and uncertainty the
Roman Catholic Church the largest
denomination of Christians worldwide has
a glorious history of the Church of
Jesus Christ as the sole Christian
Church in the west during the high and
late Middle Ages it goes on to say
explore the history of the Roman
Catholic Church before the Reformation
in this priest in this brief guide the
second in a series of articles about the
Roman Catholic Church History so we are
reading secular history with this not
even secular this is coming straight
from Catholicism
we are the church that rolls out of the
ashes of the Roman Empire
and what did that church do they mingled
with the governments with these nations
that had risen out of Rome and beloved I
need you to understand there is no
prophecy there is no prophecy in any
other religion that matches the the
level of detail of this one prophecy in
Daniel chapter 2 and beloved this is the
this is the first of of many of the
prophecies in the Book of Daniel and in
the Book of Revelation
if the testimony of the person is true
you ought to believe that person
come on
come with me I want you to see this
this mingling of church and state led to
a false belief system which false things
being taught about the Bible
such as purgatory
such as the worship of Mary
such of such as an eternally burning
hell
what we're doing in this truth series
every every fourth uh uh Sabbath of the
month we're doing this truth Series this
Evangelistic series to speak about
Doctrine to speak about truth all of the
things we've addressed so far are things
that were corrupted during the dark ages
including falsifying of the testimony of
Jesus revamping prophecy
all right
come on we're just gonna we're just
gonna get to this last part
because if you look around today beloved
and you see the rise of Christian
nationalism
I just need you to understand
we're done I need you to understand
that this rise of Christian nationalism
that we are all beholding before our
very eyes right now was prophesied by
Daniel over 2 500 years ago when he said
the iron and the clay would mingle
together
and it is this mingling together that
would ultimately bring about the second
coming of Jesus Christ
are y'all with me
the Bible says in verse 44 in the days
of these Kings talking about this
combination of church and state this
combination of iron and Clay which you
see in America especially that people
are pushing for with all this passion
and you wonder where is this coming from
people secular people wonder where is
this coming from atheistic people wonder
where is this coming from not realizing
that the Bible prophesied it
in the days of these Kings saw the god
of Heaven set up a kingdom which shall
never be destroyed and the kingdom shall
not be left to other people but it saw
breaking pieces and consume all these
kingdoms and it shall stand forever
listen y'all
listen
if
Babylon failed to meet a Persia
and Nita Persia fell to Greece as the
prophecy stated and Greece fell to Rome
as the prophecy stated and Rome
disintegrated into various kingdoms as
the prophecy stated attic and a and a
professed Christian element rolls up
among the clay as the prophecy stated
and we now see Christian nationalism
seeking to threaten
America in a way we have never seen
before as the prophecy stated and there
is much more disability I'm kind of I'm
juicing this down for you right now
believe it or not my question for you is
this
if those things all happen what are the
odds of the Stone
which represents Jesus Christ
coming to destroy the kingdoms of this
world what are the odds that that's
going to happen
you cannot believe it all you want you
can be like no you can be like but if
everything has already come to pass in
the way that the Bible said it would
what are the odds of that stone coming
out of the sky to destroy these kingdoms
that another kingdom one that lasts
forever
will be set up
the testimony of Jesus has proven true
y'all
it has proven true secular history
verifies the testimony of Jesus that
night I don't know how long I've been
preaching but that night our study
lasted for over four hours
I think some of my people are on
watching right now who were there that
night
you want to know why it lasted for four
hours because we were just blown away we
were like we were asking so many wait
what and after hearing this testimony of
Jesus which is the spirit of Prophecy
after hearing that we were like yup what
other choices there what other option do
we have now but to believe
Jesus said in John 13 9 now I tell you
19 John 13 19. now I tell you before I
come to pass it when it come to pass you
may believe that I am he
Jesus also said I am the way the truth
and the life no man comes to the father
but by me so if Jesus is truth yes our
black you were there you could testify I
was looking for you man
listen y'all
if Jesus testimony is true
then we can also trust it when he says I
am the way the truth and the life that
he means I am the way the truth and the
life not that person not that person not
that religion not that religion when he
says I am the way the truth and the life
we now have reason to believe him
foreign
Revelation 12 17 my last slide
second to last slide I'm sorry
Revelation 12 17 and the dragon was
wrong with the woman and went to make
war with the remnant ever seen which
keep the Commandments of God and have
the testimony of Jesus Christ and Jesus
tells us beloved that the end time
movement of God will have two things
he says it right here
they will keep the Commandments of God
so if you're in a church that's not
keeping the Commandments of God there's
some issues
that you're going to have to wrestle
with
what does it mean to keep the
Commandments of God there's a lot of
confusion about that you have to
understand beloved what it means to keep
the Commandments of God and number two
if you're in a church that does not un
does not have the testimony of Jesus
Christ meaning you don't understand
prophecy your church cannot tell you
this is what the prophecy state is going
to happen this is how we should
understand Revelation chapter 13 and
Revelation chapter 14 and Revelation
chapter 17 and Daniel chapter 2 and
Daniel chapter 7 and Daniel chapter 8
and Daniel chapter 9 and Daniel chapter
11 and Revelation chapters one through
seven and Revelation chapter 20. if your
church can't tell you that I'm not
saying that the people in that church
are lost because you don't have to
understand prophecy in order to be saved
don't get me wrong
all I'm talking about is the system
if you're in a system that is
incorrectly interpreting prophecy you're
in a system that does not have the
spirit of Prophecy does not have the
testimony of Jesus
if you're in a system that says you
don't need to keep the Commandments of
God or or telling you the the that
they've been nailed away done away at
the cross you're in the wrong system
doesn't mean you're lost it just means
what you're following is not what Jesus
ordained
if you're an atheist if you're an
agnostic and you're like man I don't
know if God exists
I've heard prophecy before and it
doesn't match up it's because you
haven't heard genuine prophecy what
you've heard is a convolution of genuine
prophecy what you've heard is that left
behind stuff what you've heard is that
you know oh Israel was restored as a
nation in in 1948 and that what you've
heard is stuff that doesn't add up to
the scripture and stuff that doesn't add
up even in history
foreign
there's my last slide
I hope you can see the passion in that
face
it is a testimony of Jesus
that brought me
from that first slide
to this right here
it is a testimony of Jesus
that led me to drop the old microphone
for a new microphone
it is a testimony of Jesus the most
powerful testimony I've ever heard and
still here to this day
that inspires my passion to spread the
truth
because beloved there is such a thing
as truth
and I pray that today
for those of you listening I pray that
today
if you have never heard truth before
you heard it today
I'm in I invite you like I was invited
20 plus years ago
to search this truth y'all
that atheist man said this if there is
one prophecy that can be proven that
could not have been manipulated
to be fulfilled
that is clearly it can be clearly
demonstrated that was written before it
came to pass then sign me up my appeal
to you today you watching this today are
you watching this down sometime in the
future sign up y'all
trust me
you will not go wrong with the word of
God you will not go wrong with the Bible
sign up I know there are things well the
Bible says and this prophecy didn't come
to pass I know it's because you don't
understand it right now
so so I get the passion for rejecting it
oh you know it contradicts it's because
you're not you have not understood it in
the way that it was designed to be
understood and so I get the rejection
but I'm telling you
I pray that after hearing this tonight
good today go back search this prophecy
out for yourself
go see for yourself nah a meter person
didn't really overthrow Babylon it was
somebody else go check it out test it
kick the tires do what you need to do
but when you find that the testimony is
true
I plead with you sign up
the god
who is the god of the future
knows the thoughts that he has towards
you
and he wants to see you saved in his
kingdom
sign up
God is waiting for you
Heavenly Father
thank you for speaking to us
thank you Lord for sowing for sharing
your testimony
with us
that we might believe
that you are here that you are the one
that you
are God
thank you Lord for hearing
and for testifying
thank you
for your desire to see us all saved
Lord we have one enemy it's not each
other our enemy is the devil
who's seeking to sow confusion who's
seeking to to sow division
Lord I pray that we might rise above
that
and become United
on the same page with you is my prayer
in Jesus name
amen and amen
God bless you
um I want to invite you if this is the
first time you're hearing these truths
and you want to go deeper in the Bible
study please
reach out to our living man a Bible
worker Bible working team uh we'll
connect with you we will study with you
if you want to know more about the Book
of Daniel about these prophecies reach
out to us
if you want to give your life to Christ
for the first time please reach out to
us if if you want to be baptized if you
want to to to to to give your life fully
to the Lord please reach out to us uh we
are online church and we are we're here
for you
we're here for some for those of you who
may never step foot in an actual Church
we're here for those of you who are just
confused and trying to find truth reach
out to us let's connect and may God
bless you and may God lead you in your
search for truth
I'm going to put up a chat for um
alter live so for those of you who would
like to join us for alter live we
welcome you uh that sat will go up uh
the the link will go up in the chat here
and um
there there we go
and again we're gonna sign off God bless
you and uh we'll see you next week by
the grace of God